Guide to the Kirk Winslow Papers MSS.317
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kirk Winslow Papers
1960-2004
Fales Library and Special Collections
Winslow, Kirk
MSS.317
12 Linear Feet in 11 records cartons, 1 flat box, and 2 oversize folders
4 Cassettes
Kirk Winslow (1955-2002) was a graduate of New York University's Cinema Studies Program and a filmmaker and photographer with ties to several well-known artists. This collection consists of photos, slides, contact sheets, and negatives Winslow used to create works such as "Postwar," "Democracy in America," and "Cost of Living," plus slides and photos from his international travels and personal life.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Winslow's estate, facilitated by fellow artists, to New York University after his death. Accession number associated with this donation is 2011.317.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Arrangement
Arranged into five series by format:
Series I: Slides
Series II: Photographs
Series III: Contact sheets
Series IV: Negatives
Series V: Other formats
Biographical Note
Kirk Winslow was born in 1955 in Beirut, Lebanon, the son of Maryette Charlton and Hall Winslow. Two years later, his family moved to Manhattan, where he lived most of his life. He attended the Putney School in Vermont and spent time in Europe in the 1970s. He earned a BFA in Cinema Studies from New York University and became a filmmaker and photographer, developing close ties to several well-known artists of the late 20th century.
Winslow published an article on the films of Gregory J. Markopoulos, in whom he had a life-long interest, in Millennium Film Journal in 1998 and presented a Markopoulos retrospective in Germany in 1999. He held a rare public screening of his films at the Robert Beck Memorial Cinema one year before his death. A later series of films by Markopoulos and Robert Beavers was dedicated to Winslow's memory. Kirk Winslow died in Manhattan in 2002.
Related Materials
The Richard Foreman Papers (MSS 152) contain two films by Kirk Winslow, "Rhoda in Potatoland" and "The Threepenny Opera, Lincoln Center highlights."
Scope and Contents
The Kirk Winslow Papers (1960-2004) document Winslow's creative process and work as a filmmaker and photographer during the late 20th century. Included are slides, photographs, negatives, and contact sheets from his time in Manhattan, the Hamptons, Washington, D.C., and Europe. Also included are audio cassettes that accompany specific slide carousels, photography books inscribed to him, and signed posters.
filmmaking; Art Photography; Slides (photographs); Black-and-white negatives.; Black-and-white photographs.; Contact sheets.
- Series I: Slides, 1970-2004; 8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of slides for several of Winslow's projects including "Democracy in America", "Cost of Living", and "Post War", plus slides of swans, flowers, clouds, individuals, architecture, objects, and locations in the United States and Europe.
  - Slides (Box 1, Folder 1-17)
  - Slides (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - Slides: Democracy in America (Box 3, Folder 1-13)
  - Slides (Box 4, Folder 1-8, Case 1-3)
  - Slides: Cost of Living (Box 5, Folder 1-4, Case 1-4)
  - Slides (Box 6, Case 1-3)
  - Slides: Democracy in America (Box 7, Case 1-5)
  - Slides (Box 8, Case 1-5)
- Series II: Photographs, 1960-2003; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Series II contains color and black and white photos of and by Kirk Winslow, including Winslow's copyrighted 1980s photos of Manhattan music club CBGB and performance artist Tim Miller. Also here are photos from Europe and New York City neighborhoods and buildings, plus photos of interiors and furnishings as well as some abstract photos.
  - Photographs (Box 9, Folder 4-37)
  - Photographs, uncut (Box 11, Case 1-2)
  - Photographs (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series III: Contact Sheets, 1970-1995; .5 Linear Feet
  Series III contains contact sheets, most unmarked and undated, for black and white shots of Manhattan locations, interiors, individuals drama performances, and performance artists. Some sheets are titled "Sunspot" by John Jesurun, the Kitchen, NYC, March 1989. Others are of performance artist Stuart Sherman.
  - Contact Sheets (Box 9, Folder 38-47)
  - Contact Sheets (Box 10, Folder 4-8)
- Series IV: Negatives, 1970-1995; 1 Linear Feet
  Series IV contains color and black and white negatives, most undated and unmarked, of film shot by Winslow.
  - Negatives (Box 9, Folder 9, 10, 17, 21, 40, 45, 47)
  - Negatives (Box 10, Folder 1-11, Case 1-4)
  - Negatives (Box 11, Case 1-4)
  - Negatives (Box 12, Folder 1, 4-6)
- Series V: Other formats, 1968-1995; 1 Linear Feet
  Series V contains processed uncut rolls of film, a few letters, three inscribed photography books, five posters, and four audiocassettes that accompany several of Winslow's slide carousels.
  - Office papers, postcards, photocopies (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Photography books, audiocassettes (Box 11)
  - Graphic art (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Poster (Flat-file-folder 15)
  - Poster (Box Shared Fales 078, Folder 10)